And welcome back. In this lecture, we will integrate our MCP server with the cloud desktop.
All the steps that I'm going to say are documented in this guide. So please go through it in a step-by-step.
So the way to tell the cloud desktop about our MCP server is usually through a configuration file.
This configuration file is located in Mac OS under library application support/cloud.
And the file name itself for the configuration file. It's called the cloud under score
desktop under score config.json. In this JSON configuration, we tell the cloud about the location
of Python interpreter. And as we said in this guide, if you don't know the location of that,
you can simply find it by typing which Python internal. Next, we tell the cloud desktop the
location of the MCP server code. You should have the clone the MCP server code in a previous lecture.
And notice that this needs to be the full path of the file. Finally, we set two environment
variable, your contentful access token as well as your space ID. Now, after having your JSON
file ready with your data, you need to quit, load up and reopen it for the configuration to take
effect. So let me start my app. If you see connection errors on the top right of the screen,
do not panic. We would have a whole trouble-shooting lecture coming up next.
Now, if we click on search and tools over here, we should see our contentful MCP server,
as well as the two exposed MCP tools over here. Okay, let's give it a try. And here in the prompt,
I'm going to ask, list all my contentful entries, put them in a basic table with a markdown format.
Let me hit enter. And as we said, the AI uses doc string to decide which tool to call. Now,
you can see it asks me for a permission to invoke a tool from third party integration. I'm going to
click on allow once.
And we can see the model successfully listed the entries and put them in a table as I requested.
Now, let's test our second MCP tool. And I want to get the data from this entry ID. So in the prompt,
I'm going to ask, can you give me the data of this entry ID? And then summarize it for me.
And as we can see, cloud desktop right now, or the MCP client embedded inside the cloud cloud
desktop, it wants to invoke my second MCP server tool. And it asked me for permission to do so.
So I'm going to click again on allow once. And in the meantime, please remember what I mentioned
earlier about attack vector. Every user input is a potential secure theorist. We will deep dive
into those risk in section two. But for now, try to enjoy the fact that we have successfully
connected an AI to your external system through MCP server. I'm going to see you in the next
lecture, where we add MCP resources. I hope that this lecture has been informative for you.
And I will see you in the next one. Thanks for watching.